Kevin L. Miller, Ph.D.

klmille@gmail.com | (310) 562-4572 | Los Angeles, CA 90230

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/kevin-miller-phd-1b197986/ | GitHub: github.com/Koldenblue

Portfolio: https://kevin-miller-react-portfolio.herokuapp.com/

SUMMARY

Full-Stack Web Developer with a Ph.D. in chemistry from the University of California, Los Angeles (UCLA). Education in full-stack development from UCLA. Experienced scientific thinker, researcher, and problem-solver. Values community, ethics, integrity, and good business sense, having spent years as a business manager, teacher, and scientist. Extensive teaching experience lends itself to public speaking, leadership, and teamwork skills. Top aim is to contribute to a team while continuously pursuing self-improvement. Seeks to improve the lives of teammates and clients, whether that be in the real world or the digital world.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- JavaScript/HTML/CSS used as main coding languages
- Emphasis on MERN stack technologies (MongoDB, Express, React, and Node.js) for front-end and back-end design, database management, routing, and client-server communication
- Research and use of established libraries for streamlining development, such as Redux, jQuery, Handlebars, Sass, and Bootstrap
- SQL database work, through MySQL and the Sequelize Object-Relational Mapper (ORM)
- MongoDB along with Mongoose or mongo.js, for non-relational database management
- Coding techniques include object-oriented programming, asynchronous function handling, mobileresponsive web design, and code testing with tools such as Postman, Jest, and Robo 3T
- AJAX calls for retrieving data from and integrating APIs
- Ability to quickly learn additional libraries for example, React-Spring, Moment.js, or Node Package Manager packages such as Inquirer
- Ability to quickly learn additional programming languages and techniques for example, Python and basic C/C++ programming accomplished through self-study and professional certification

PROJECTS

Color Rippler | https://bit.ly/color-rippler | https://bit.ly/color-rippler-github

- A single-handedly designed and coded art project that takes advantage of the React and Redux frameworks to efficiently render a large number of interactive components.
- Combines front-end design with algorithms and MongoDB storage for dynamic interactivity

Express Bartender | https://bit.ly/express-bartender | https://bit.ly/express-bartender-github

- Led a small team in back-end database design and storage of user information. Reviewed team code and contributed assistance to front-end website design.
- Programmed SQL database of drink recipes to cater to authenticated users. Coded database queries to add, modify, and delete user recipes. Acquired initial database information using API calls.

Inform and React | https://bit.ly/inform-react | https://bit.ly/inform-react-github

- Executed lead back-end scripting for a small team of coders, helping others solve code difficulties. Programmed all routes and led database design. Performed code review and overall project design.
- Designed and coded a React-driven app with a goal of providing voter information. Programmed AJAX calls to API databases, database storage with MongoDB, and user authentication routes.

EMPLOYMENT

Twinwood, Inc.:

Property Manager and Accountant

October 2013 - August 2020

- Rigorous documentation and coordination of construction projects, with spending in the hundreds of thousands, benefited both tenants and the company through substantial property improvement
- Contributed to business decision making, such as management of over a dozen buildings, and purchasing decisions for properties worth millions
- Meticulous business analytics helped achieve a yearly company growth rate of 3.6% of net worth

Praxair:

Lab Technician and Analytical Scientist

October 2014 - February 2015

• Carefully managed lab testing allowed for a fast throughput of dozens of highly pure gasses daily

University of California, Los Angeles:

Researcher / Teaching Assistant

Sept. 2007 - December 2014

- Intense scientific research led to seven published research papers
- Personal mentoring of two undergraduates helped them publish their own scientific papers
- Chemistry research was awarded Ralph and Charlene Bauer Award, as well as two separate fellowship awards
- Close supervision of hundreds of undergraduate students in both labs and discussion sections, during teaching of over a dozen college-level chemistry discussion courses

EDUCATION

CS50 Professional Certificate - HarvardX Online Full-Stack Web Development Coding Bootcamp - UCLA Extension Ph.D., Chemistry - University of California, Los Angeles B.S., Chemistry - University of California, Irvine